billiardsboutique.com 2019-07-14

# Privacy policy - Billiards Boutique

This is the privacy notice of BilliardsBoutique.com, legal name Mr P. Williams T/as Billiards Boutique.

We respect your privacy and are determined to protect your personal data. The purpose of this privacy notice is to inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from). We’ll also tell you about your privacy rights and how the data protection law protects you.

### 1\. WHO WE ARE AND IMPORTANT INFORMATION 

**What is the purpose of this privacy notice?**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of our website www.billiardsboutique.com, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our email newsletter, sign up for product alerts, purchase a product or service or take part in a competition or giveaway.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

You must read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

**Data controller**

Mr P. Williams T/as Billiards Boutique is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as ["Billiards Boutique"], "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice). 

**Our contact details are:** Billiards Boutique Suite 4 (Above Easton Motors), Yeats Road, Portland, Dorset, DT5 2EN and our telephone number is 01305 458071. 

For all data matters contact Our Data Representative, Mr Peter Williams on [pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com](mailto:pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com) or 01305 458071 during office hours.

Mr P. Williams T/As Billiards Boutique is the data controller and responsible for this website known as billiardsboutique.com.

**Third-party links outside of our control**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. 

When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

### 2\. THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. You can find out more about personal data from the [Information Commissioners Office](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows :

We may process certain types of personal data about you as follows:

**Identity Data** may include your first name, maiden name, last name, username, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.

**Contact Data**  may include your billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.

**Financial Data** may include your bank account and payment card details.

**Transaction Data** may include details about payments between us and other details of purchases made by you.

**Technical Data** may include your login data, internet protocol addresses, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, time zone setting and location, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this site.

**Profile Data** may include your username and password, purchases or orders, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.

**Usage Data** may include information about how you use our website, products and services.

**Marketing and Communications Data** may include your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We may also collect, use and share  **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

**We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**If you fail to provide personal data  **

Where we need to collect your personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

### 3\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA 

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through: 

Direct interactions: You may provide data by filling in forms on our site (or otherwise) or by communicating with us by post, phone, email or otherwise, including when you:

  * order our products or services;
  * create an account on our site;
  * subscribe to our service or publications;
  * request resources or marketing be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, prize draw, promotion or survey; or
  * give us feedback.

**Automated technologies or interactions:** As you use our site, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and usage patterns. We collect this data by using cookies, server logs and similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites that use our cookies. Please see our [cookie policy](https://www.billiardsboutique.com/pages/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy")  for further details.

**Third parties or publicly available sources:** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below.

  * Technical Data from the following parties:
  * analytics providers such as Google, Klaviyo and Shopify based outside the EU;
  * advertising networks such as Google, Bing and Facebook based outside the EU; and Criteo based inside the EU.
  * Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Shopify Payments and PayPal based inside or outside the EU. Or V12 Finance based within the United Kingdom.
  * Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.

### 4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * **Performance of Contract** this means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract. Such as when you place an order with us and we need to deliver those goods.

  * **Legitimate Interest** this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by emailing pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com.

  * **Comply with a legal or regulatory obligations**  this means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting Pete Williams on pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, with the legal bases we rely on to do so. 

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact Pete Williams on pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below. 

Purpose/Activity

| 

Type of data

| 

Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
  
---|---|---  
  
To register you as a new customer

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To process and deliver your order including:  
(a) Manage payments, fees and charges  
(b) Collect and recover money owed to us 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Financial  
(d) Transaction  
(e) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to recover debts owed to us   
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:  
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy  
(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Usage  
(e) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business   
  
To administer and protect our business and our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Technical 

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation   
  
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure and understand the effectiveness of our advertising 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Usage  
(e) Marketing and Communications  
(f) Technical 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy   
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences 

| 

(a) Technical  
(b) Usage 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy   
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you 

| 

(a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Technical  
(d) Usage  
(e) Profile 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to develop our products/services and grow our business   
  
**Marketing  **

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. 

We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

**Promotional offers from us**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you.

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**Third-party marketing**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside of Billiards Boutique

**Opting out**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting [pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com](mailto:pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com) at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product OR service experience or other transactions.

**Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.billiardsboutique.com/pages/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please get in touch with Pete Williams via email on pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### 5\. WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

**External Third Parties Service**

    * Providers, acting as processors, based outside the EU who provide IT and system administration services. These include: Shopify (our website platform provider), Klaviyo (our email marketing provider), Beans (administer our loyalty rewards).
    * Professional advisers, acting as processors or joint controllers, including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the United Kingdom who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
    * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities, acting as processors or joint controllers, based in the United Kingdom, who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
    * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### 6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

Countries outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) do not always offer the same levels of protection to your personal data, so European law has prohibited transfers of personal data outside of the EEA unless the transfer meets certain criteria.

Many of our third party service providers are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we do our best to ensure a similar degree of security of data by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission; or
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts or codes of conduct or certification mechanisms approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe; or
  * Where we use providers based in the United States, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

If none of the above safeguards is available, we may request your explicit consent to the specific transfer. You will have the right to withdraw this consent at any time.

Please email us at [pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com](mailto:pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com) if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

### 7\. DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### 8\. DATA RETENTION

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

For example: By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by emailing pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com or are set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your legal rights below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### 9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

Unless subject to an exemption under the data protection laws, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: 

  * The right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold about you;
  * The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
  * The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary to retain such data;
  * The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, where consent was the lawful basis for processing your data; 
  * The right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), where applicable i.e. where our processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of our contract with you or where we process your data by automated means); 
  * The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
  * The right to object to our processing of personal data, where applicable i.e. where processing is based on our legitimate interests (or in performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing or processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics).

You can see more about these rights at: [https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact our Data Representative, Pete Williams on pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com

**No fee required – with some exceptions**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable admin fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### 10\. Changes to this notice and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated on 08 May 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.

Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. 

### 11\. Queries, requests or concerns

To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints in relation to this policy or any other data protection matter between you and us, please in the first instance contact our Data Representative on pete.williams@billiardsboutique.com.

If this does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the [Information Commissioners Office](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/) on 03031231113 or via email [https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/) or at the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF, England, UK.
